

Oleksandr Voievudko

Frontend / React Developer

I have been working as a manager in game industry for the last 8 years but now I decided to change the direction of my carrier. Development always has been my passion and hobby for more than 5 years since I wrote the first script for my team to automate their work. I have spent a lot of time learning JavaScript and React particularly and now I am looking for new opportunities to turn my hobby into the real job.

alex.voievudko@gmail.com

Barcelona, Spain

linkedin.com/in/alex-voievudko

+34 (638) 115 293

alex-voievudko.github.io/portfolio

github.com/alex-voievudko

SKILLS



COURSES & CERTIFICATIONS

React.js Essential Training - LinkedIn (08/2022)

React.js: Building an Interface - LinkedIn (08/2022)

Complete React Developer in 2022 (w/ Redux, Hooks, GraphQL) - Udemy (02/2022)

Node.js API Masterclass With Express & MongoDB (04/2022)

MERN Stack Front To Back: Full Stack React, Redux & Node.js (12/2021)

React - The Complete Guide (incl Hooks, React Router, Redux) (08/2021)

React + Redux - Professional Development - Udemy (05/2020)

Complete React Course for Creating Amazing UI - Udemy (12/2019)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Player XP Team Lead

Tilting Point

12/2020 - 08/2022

Achievements/Tasks

Barcelona, Spain

- Building in-house Player Support and Community teams
- Developing a strategical vision for future team growth
- Setting goals to the team & doing annual reviews
- Managing and monitoring day to day operations of the teams
- Hiring and mentoring new people
- Implement new technologies, tools and automation to increase team efficiency

Project Manager

Plarium

08/2019 - 12/2020 Achievements/Tasks Kharkiv, Ukraine

- Initiated and launched a ChatBot project to increase Customer Support team productivity
- Initiated and launched the tool to process Google Play review resulting in 66% of all reviews being processed using machine learning algorithms
- Coordinating and planning project activities related to plarium.com development
- Creating and maintaining project timelines
- Gathering and documenting project requirements
- Interacting with internal associates and departments

WORK EXPERIENCE

Community Management General Lead

Plarium

12/2018 - 08/2019 Achievements/Tasks Kharkiv, Ukraine

- Helping a director of the department to lead and manage a team of 53 members including Player Support Representatives, VIP Account Managers, Community Managers, Translators, and Content Creators
- Analyzing the efficiency of the department and propose solutions to improve and automate team processes
- Strategical planning of the department growing
- Setting short terms and long terms goals to teams
- Ensuring all teams are properly equipped with necessary technical resources and tools

Senior Customer Support Team Lead

Plarium

10/2015 - 12/2018

Lviv. Ukraine

- Achievements/Tasks
- Leading and coaching three Team Leads
- Collating and analyzing data to identify strategies for improvement of service and productivity
- Implemented improvements including a new help desk system and several internal tools
- Integrated help desk system to several game titles including Raid: Shadow Legends to provide instant support for players
- Automated team routine tasks to increase the productivity
- Established knowledge base to decrease the ticket volume

Customer Support Team Lead

Plarium

04/2014 - 10/2015

Lviv, Ukraine

- Achievements/TasksHiring a team
- Leading and managing a team of 20 customer service agents
- Planning, assigning and monitoring work tasks for optimum team efficiency
- Performing monthly staff performance evaluations
- Identifying and addressing development needs
- Developing staff training programs and reference manuals

EDUCATION

Specialist, General Physics

Ivan Franko National University of Lviv

09/2007 - 05/2012 Lviv, Ukraine

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Budget App (08/2022)

- This is a simple budget app that allows to create different kind of budget categories and track your expenses

Full Professional Proficiency

- **Demo:** https://alex-voievudko.github.io/budget-app/

World of Games (08/2022)

- This is an app that allows to view list of popular games and games developers. The app uses firebase auth for user registration and log in system and also RAWG
 API for fetching game and developers data
- Demo: https://630373690c37ff00a8b2348c--world-of-games.netlify.app/

LANGUAGES

Full Professional Proficiency

Russian

Ukrainian

Native or Bilingual Proficiency